Ray Rezaeifar

Registered Professional Engineer (P.E.), Texas Houston, TX, USA 832-530-9394

Ray.rezaeifar@gmail.com

Project Engineer

Professional Summary:

Ray has more than 20 years of experience in Oil & Gas, Onshore and Offshore facilities, Midstream, Downstream, LNG, Chemical, Pipeline, Sea Line, and Power Generation industries. Ray's duties have included project engineer, lead piping engineer, and mechanical engineer.

Education:

- MBA, Purdue University Global, IN, USA, 2016
- Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering, IUST University, 1999

Areas of Expertise:

- In depth knowledge of industry codes, standards and guidelines such as ASME, ANSI, ASTM, API, NACE, AWWA, AWS, NFPA
- Lead project teams for engineering and procurement of capital and expense projects
- Prepare SOW, EWP, CWP, quality and technical specifications
- Estimate and monitor project budgets and costs, WBS, schedules and prepare project execution plan (PEP)
- Set priorities for project goals and schedules and direct in a safe, efficient, cost effective and timely manner to be completed within deadlines
- Develop and monitor risks
- Prepare offers, matrixes and bid marketing supports for products and services
- Provide procurement and resourcing services including selection and management supplier/vendor, contracting and negotiation, and follow up on vendor submissions and jobs quality and follow up procurement strategy, invoices and tender documents (technical and financial
- Prepare and monitor MOMs, progress and status reports, punch lists of incomplete works and obtain final acceptances

Work history:

❖ Worley/Jacobs Project Engineer

Houston, TX Nov. 2017 to May 2020 Worked on various projects and programs like BP WBU, Chevron OASIS, Chevron Anchor, Shell Whale, ExxonMobil Tight Oil, ExxonMobil Dock 5, Flint Hills GOHT, Marathon Galveston Bay Refinery (GBR), and Corpus Christi Polymers (CCP). The responsibilities include, but are not limited to

- Participated in the projects scope definition
- Developed cost estimation, forecasts, budget, WBS, schedule, and project deliverables
- Led disciplines from technical point of views and followed up project deliverables
- Prepared reports
- Determined risks, assumption logs and acceptance criteria
- Followed up Inquiries, and purchases and vendor deliverables
- Implemented approved actions & changes, and work Packages
- Attended in HAZOP and model review meetings

❖ S&B Engineers and Constructors

Houston, TX

May 2017 to Nov. 2017

Lead Piping Engineer

- Calculated, prepared, and developed project documents such as piping classes, piping components and valve technical requirements for purchase, valves test procedure, piping specialty items
- Prepared Line list
- Reviewed and evaluated technical bids (TBE)
- Provided clarifications and technical negotiations, and reviewed vendor prints.
- Followed up on vendor submissions and jobs quality.
- Supported job site and fabricators activities by answering technical queries.
- Cooperated and coordinated with other disciplines.

❖ Bechtel Oil, Gas & Chemicals Project Engineer

Houston, TX Aug. 2013 to May 2016

Chevron's Wheatstone LNG plant:

- Organized, supervised and reviewed piping and materials engineering groups for preparation and development of the project documents, specifications, calculations, Materials, Valves and Gasket selections, drawings and material take off
- Ensured the project conforms to the client's approved basis of design and all applicable regulatory and code requirements
- Produced discipline forecast man-hours and monitored discipline budget and schedule
- Determined risks, Prepared assumption and issue logs, developed piping WBS, worked in a team to develop budget, schedule
- Gathered work performance data
- Prepared piping material requisitions (MR), reviewed and evaluated technical bids (TBE), Technical negotiation with vendors, Expedited vendor drawings and submissions, and followed up and monitored vendor jobs quality
- Attended in project 3D model review meetings

- Prepared and reviewed project variation orders
- Prepared and monitored progress reports and punch lists of incomplete works
- Very close cooperation and coordination with other engineering, procurement, fabricators and construction disciplines as well as vendors/suppliers, contractors and Client for various activities to support and follow up goals and deliverables

Ventech Engineers LLC Lead Piping Engineer

Pasadena, TX Dec. 2012 to Aug. 2013

Dakota Prairie oil refining:

- Responsible for design, calculation and preparation piping engineering specifications, documents, calculations, materials and valves selections, drawings and material take off
- Produced discipline forecast man-hours and monitored discipline budget and schedule
- Technical bid evaluations of piping & components
- Resolved vendor technical queries on piping components
- Supported, collaborated and coordinated with other engineering, procurement, fabricators and construction disciplines as well as vendors/suppliers, contractors and Client for various activities and follow up goals and deliverables

Petropars Ltd.

Project Engineer

Dec. 2007 to Oct. 2012

South Pars Gas Field Development Phase 12 including onshore and offshore facilities and Sea lines (3 x 32" and 3 x 6" piggy back lines) from offshore to onshore facilities and 2 x 30" Sea line from the onshore to export and measuring facilities, Pipelines (3 x 56") from onshore facility to other Gas Treatment Plants:

- Led and guided disciplines in resolving technical issues
- Participated in the projects scope definition
- Developed cost estimation, forecasts, budget, WBS, schedule, and project deliverables
- Prepared reports
- Attended in the HAZOP and model review meetings
- Determined high-level risks, assumption logs and acceptance criteria
- Followed up Inquiries, and purchases
- Implemented approved actions & changes, and work Packages

❖ Nargan Engineers & Constructors

Senior Piping Engineer

Jul. 2005 to Dec. 2007

Bandar Abbas oil refinery:

• Prepared and reviewed engineering documents specifications, calculations, drawings, proposals and bid evaluations

* Sazeh Consultants Co.,

Piping Engineer

Aug. 1999 to Jul. 2005

Petrochemical PVC & HDPE plants:

• Prepared and reviewed engineering documents, specifications, calculations, drawings, proposals and bid evaluations

Software:

• SmartPlant SPRD, Pipeworks, PDMS, NAVIS Work, Caesar II, Auto CAD, MS Office

Certificates:

- Registered Professional Engineer (P.E.), Mechanical, TBPE, 2015
- PMI, 2017
- The Project Management PrepCastTM, PMI-OSP International LLC, 2018
- The Project Management Principles, 2009
- The Risk Management Principles, 2009
- Six Sigma Process Improvement (Yellow Belt), 2015
- ASME B31.3, Process Piping, Atlanta, GA, 2014
- ASME B31.4, Pipeline Transportation Systems for Liquid Hydrocarbons and Other Liquids, Houston, TX, 2015
- ASME B31.8, Gas Transportation and Distribution Piping Systems, Houston, TX, 2015